Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Episode 7
Farewell to the Solar System
Message from Project Chief Todo.
So you're already out there, at the edge of the Solar System?
The journey to Iscandar is lengthy.
We have only taken the first step.
True.
But word that you've destroyed the
Pluto base has reached Earth.
There will be no more planet bombs.
You have no idea how much relief that's brought.
Just knowing the Yamato is heading for Iscandar helps us keep going.
So, Okita, retrieve the Cosmo Reverse System.
Earth awaits the Yamato's return.
It awaits your return!
The heliopause is starting to interfere with our communications.
Give me five minutes to prepare everything for hyperspace transmission.
It's rare to see you alone.
I thought the XO would be with you.
You must have a lot of free time.
Unless there's trouble on board,
security doesn't have much to do.
How are things going for you?
There isn't much for me to do until we reach a new star system.
I've heard that you've begun counseling the crew.
Maybe you could spend some therapy time with me?
Stop joking around.
Once past the heliopause, we'll be unable to communicate with Earth anymore, right?
The captain should let everyone send at least one final message there.
If he did, it could just make everyone more homesick.
Keep at it, then.
This is the updated shipboard duty list?
Hey...
Back on Enceladus, didn't you ask me something strange?
Are you related to any aliens?
Did you mean Sasha?
At first, I wasn't sure what you meant.
But you saw her on Mars, didn't you?
That's why I wondered.
Yeah, she looked a lot like you.
Sasha Iscandar...
The woman who gave her life to bring us
the Wave Motion Engine's activation core.
Come to think of it, wasn't there another who arrived a year earlier?
To bring the plans for the Wave Motion Engine itself?
Yurisha Iscandar.
Her name.
A last message to Earth?
Yes. Once we've passed the heliopause,
powerful cosmic radiation will
prevent communication with Earth.
So I've decided to let anyone who chooses, speak with their family.
Really?
Simultaneously,
we'll hold a line-crossing ceremony as we leave the Solar System.
Line-crossing is observed at the Equator, but this is space.
Once, sailors performed line-crossing ceremonies
when traversing the Equator, to ask for their ships' safety.
We shall do the same.
But Ota said you wear costumes to a traditional line-crossing ceremony.
So he put you up to it, huh?
You believe anything you're told, Mako.
Where did you go, Ota?!
Honestly, you shouldn't listen to a word he says.
Well, I think it looks good on you.
Thank you!
Everyone, because of your efforts, Operation M-2 was a success.
No more planet bombs will strike Earth.
As your captain, I thank you.
We now begin the Solar System line-crossing ceremony.
But our voyage has only just begun.
Once this is over, do not look back toward Earth.
Look ahead.
Keep your eye on the path that leads to Iscandar!
I pray for the line-crossing ceremony's success.
Cheers!
Want a drink, too?
I cannot drink.
You're no fun...
Supply Officer Hirata.
I was his classmate at the officer training academy.
Thank you for agreeing to my request.
If you dislike being a pilot, you're always welcome to come back.
The deck crew drew the short straw...
Ship repairs are our top priority.
So we don't get to talk to the folks back on Earth.
Akemi!
No talking on duty.
Yes, sir! It's just that I—
Enomoto!
Kodai?
What's up? You need something?
I mean, do you require something, sir?
If anyone wants to speak to their family, I'll switch with them.
But you...
Oh, man.
Is that an order?
Enomoto!
Well, that means one person will get to contact Earth.
No, two.
Isn't that...
Yes, the one who took out the
Garmillas base with Lieutenant Kodai.
Hello, there.
Looks like the tactical officer has gotten better at dealing with women.
What?
Saeki! Kishima!
You guys just got married, right? Trade places with them.
Thank you sir!
Captain, did you need something?
No, you look busy. Sorry to have bothered you.
Oh, no!
I don't know what's so fun...
The Yamato will now be traversing the heliopause.
The ship may experience some turbulence.
All crew at the line-crossing ceremony, please take care.
Something wrong, Captain?
Oh, no...
Do you need something?
No, it isn't that.
I'm sorry for bothering you.
This way to the comms room, to talk to Earth.
Now that it's finally happening, I don't know what to tell them.
It's fine... Just show them you're okay.
Don't you have...
A mother and younger brother. My dad...
I remember. He passed away during
the first encounter with the Garmillans.
My child's been born...
Man, we spent all our time just thinking of a name!
It's your turn, Engine Officer Tokugawa.
My turn?
It's Grandpa!
Oh, Aiko!
How are you? Tasuke, where are Hikoshichi and Kikuko?
Um, well...
They went to stand in line for food.
Tasuke, I'm hungry!
Just a little longer.
Recently, food hasn't been available as often.
So they're getting it from the black market—
What?
I told them to avoid the contraband so many times!
We know... We know, but we have no choice!
When will you be back, Grandpa?
A year... A year, and then I'll bring back presents.
Tasuke, look after Aiko. Earth's fate rests with you young people.
Come on... Man up, and be strong.
Tasuke, Grandpa is crying, too!
Jiro?
Daisuke!
Where's Mom?
Visiting Auntie at the hospital. She'll be back soon.
Oh, I see, but I don't have much time.
This might be my last message to you.
Don't say that!
Don't be selfish.
Tell Mom that I'll see my mission through, just like Dad would've wanted.
And I'll return to Earth, no matter what. Jiro, take care of Mom.
It's almost time.
I'm back.
Mom, it's Daisuke!
Daisuke's here?
Mom... Wait! Just a little longer.
Mom! Mom!
Daisuke!
Did you already talk to Earth?
No.
Sure you don't want to?
I'm sure.
I really am fine.
Could your parents be...
Marsnoids? Yes, you can tell by my eye color.
My grandmother was born on Mars.
The Second Inner Planet War occurred right around when I was born.
After that, we were forced to move to Earth.
I see. So you have family on Earth?
No, they were all killed by the planet bombs.
I had one brother left who died in battle with the Garmillans.
So please don't worry about it.
Just like me.
What kind of joke is this?
Well? Her father owns Morita Pharmaceuticals.
Your father says he knows a high-ranking official with a nice daughter, but I think...
Mother, consider our current situation.
You're the one who won't grasp the situation. You will take over the company.
I won't do it! And I'll choose my own wife.
All you need to do is what I tell you!
Kozo...!
Yasuo, come home safely. Please...
Please forgive me. I already have someone I've decided to marry.
Looks like Nanbu's done.
There are about twenty-eight people left.
Right, got it. By the way, I was glad to hear it.
That you got permission for that thing you mentioned.
Thank you!
Good luck. I'll put in a request when it's ready.
Sure! Anyway, it was great that the captain let us talk to Earth.
Actually, the one who recommended it to him was...
Me?
Am I wrong? Didn't you suggest it to the captain?
Security likes to ask questions, doesn't it?
Shouldn't you be calling Earth, as well?
I know.
That said, he's watching you...
Once the Yamato leaves the heliopause, we can no longer contact Earth.
Anyone wishing to, who has not completed the request form,
He needs to relax...
please do so at once.
You know I can't drink.
Sure you don't want to go, Captain?
There's no going back for me.
My dad will just tell me how I have to take over the temple.
Mine died in the first wave of planet bombing.
I hated him. He was always yelling.
But now, I find I think of him a lot. Always the times he yelled at me.
Jeez...
This is a lot of work.
There isn't much for me to do until we reach a new star system.
May i ask something?
Why didn't you volunteer for the pilot squad first?
I did, but the squad captain didn't want to let me.
You mean Kato? Why not?
He may not look it, but he's more sensitive than most to matters of life and death.
Come back alive!
Yes, sir!
Thank you...
I think he didn't want me dying in combat like my brother.
Those two were good friends. My brother and Captain Kato.
Sorry to interrupt, but could you go around, to assist the port side?
All right, all right.
Roger!
No!
You won't get away.
Ota... I told you to pour me a drink.
Please, no!
You'd better drink too!
We will soon be completing our messages to Earth.
Help me!
Anyone wishing to speak to Earth, report to the communications room.
That's...
You look well.
How is Okita? I asked Doctor Sado to take care of him.
He's been much calmer lately.
I see.
I am very grateful to you for taking care of me over this past year.
Come back alive, all right?
Yes.
Come in.
Is that you, Tokugawa?
Do you have a moment?
It's already been a year, huh?
Yamazaki mentioned that you dropped by the engine room.
Well, I...
Were you looking for this?
Tokugawa...
Do you remember our first ship?
Defense ship #36, a tiny ship they didn't even name.
We were both so young.
Since then, how many young ones have died while we're kept living?
I don't even want to count... No, I cannot allow myself to count.
People's lives are more than mere numbers.
Yes.
All we survivors can do...
...is ensure the young ones still have a hope for tomorrow.
That's all we can do to atone for taking so many of their lives.
Good job on the repair work.
I could see you.
I didn't have anything to do.
Why didn't you talk to Earth?
My whole family's dead.
What about you? Were you able to reach home?
I guess I'm the same as you.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Don't apologize.
I can't recall my past...
All I can remember is this past year. I have no memories prior to that.
I see.
The Yamato will now pass through the heliopause.
At that time, the Solar System
line-crossing ceremony will be complete.
Moving on...
Hello! We now bring you the first edition of YRA Radio Yamato!
Your host is everyone's favorite,
Yuria Misaki! Let's begin our first song.
An oldie but goodie, perfect for the end of the line-crossing ceremony.
Know that I'll return.
A bright red scarf.
On that day, come meet me once again.
For now, I dream amongst the stars,
at the end of the universe.
When he travels, a man's eyes should always be full of romance.
Safe Travels
A bright red scarf.
Farewell, Earth.
We will return.
We are going to come back!
Then there's no problem, yes? You're Earth's last remaining hope.
I'm counting on you, Lieutenant Niimi.
That girl was waving
A bright red scarf
Who do you think it was for?
Whoever it was
It doesn’t matter
Let each think it was for him
The hearts of men beginning a journey
Want a piece of romance
A bright red scarf
A trap waits in the skies.
Dark clouds gather, and up ahead, a red sun looms.
Its mouth is filled with burning fire,
and its arms are Hell's crimson flames.
Fire one blast,
to break through an inescapable trap, and effect an impossible escape.
Next time: Wish Upon a Star.
There are 343 days left before humanity is extinct.